# Collin Whalen

Front-End Developer

Saint Paul, MN (612) 517-6792 whalencollin@gmail.com

### **PROJECTS**

### **Capital Opulence** — A personal finance application

This application allows a user to create an account then begin tracking daily financial gains and expenses. Data entered by the user is rendered as a bar graph and stored in the user's dashboard.

https://capital-opulence.herokuapp.com/

### **Mantis Mocha** — A coffee e-commerce site

Mantis Mocha is built with the MERN stack and the Stripe payment API. A fast and customizable user experience was a top priority when developing this application. <a href="https://mantismocha.herokuapp.com/">https://mantismocha.herokuapp.com/</a>

# **Movie Finder** — Discover and watch thousands of movies

A front-end JavaScript application that utilizes two movie APIs. Movie Finder helps a user quickly find their next movie and where they can pay to watch it, based on genre. https://cassie-s.github.io/movie-finder/

### **EDUCATION**

# University of Minnesota coding boot camp, — Web development

July 2021 - Feb 2022

A rigorous 24-week program focused on gaining proficient technical programming skills essential for front and back-end website development.

# **Century College, Mahtomedi** — Nursing prerequisites/ generals

Aug 2019 - May 2021

Associates Degree.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Punch Neapolitan Pizza**, Roseville — *Cook*

Aug 2019 - Present

- Working as a team.
- Communicating with 100+ customers a shift.
- Satisfying custom orders while staying attentive to detail.
- Training new employees, our restaurant procedures, how to cook, prepare ingredients, and communicate during peak hours.

# Chipotle, Vadnais Heights — Cook

Jan 2016 - June 2018

- Completing work in a fast and high-pressure environment.
- Remaining flexible in a changing, unpredictable environment.
- Arriving early to every shift and completing duties in a timely manner.
- Training new employees in any crew member position.

### **SKILLS**

JavaScript

MERN Full Stack

(MongoDB, Express,

React, Node)

HTML

CSS and CSS frameworks

jQuery

**RESTful APIs** 

JSON (JavaScript Object

Notation)

MySQL

NoSQL

OOP

SCRUM Agile

**PDevelopment** 

Git and GitHub

Visual Studio Code

SEO (Search Engine

Optimization)

**XML** 

**REST** (Representational

State Transfer)

Responsive Web Design

Leadership

Communication

### PROFESSIONAL LINKS

Portfolio:

https://collin-w.github.io/prof

essional-portfolio/

GitHub:

https://github.com/Collin-W

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/c ollin-whalen/

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

U of M Bootcamp Badge: https://www.credly.com/badge s/2a8bod63-f435-4c70-b212-3c9ac801aed7/